(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
吾輩は1日後に最強のLIVEをする予定のVTuber!!
I'm the VTuber who's scheduled to perform the strongest LIVE in one day!!
おい!! 信じられないけど明日がLIVE当日らしいよ!?
Hey!! I can't believe it, but apparently tomorrow is the day of the LIVE!?
ここで吾輩のLIVEにまつわるやらかしエピソードを一つ紹介します
Here, I'll share one of the blunders I've made related to my LIVEs.
LIVEのために、毎回ちゃんと#(ハッシュタグ)を決めて
For every LIVE, I always decide on a hashtag...
配信画面に出せるように運営さんにあらかじめ報告するんだけど...
...and report it to the staff in advance so it can be displayed on screen.
報告した後、LIVE当日のツイートとか吾輩...
But after reporting it, when I tweet on the day of the LIVE...
毎回ちょっと間違えてタグツイートしちゃって
I always mess up the hashtag in my tweets just a little bit.
なんと吾輩の公式ハッシュタグ、X(旧Twitter)のトレンドに乗ったことないんだよね〜
Believe it or not, my official hashtag has never trended on X (formerly Twitter)!
運営さんいつもごめんね
Staff, I'm always sorry.
今回は...間違えないよ☆
This time... I won't make a mistake!
と言うことでみんな!!
So, everyone!!
LIVEの応援や当日のツイートは
To support the LIVE and for your tweets on the day,
絶対に「#ラプラス2周年LIVE」でツイートしてね!!
please, absolutely use the hashtag "#Laplus2ndAnniversaryLIVE"!!
今年こそ!! トレンド入りよろしくお願いしまーす!!
This year for sure!! Please help me get into the trends!!
あー! アイドルめんどくせぇ!!
Ah! Being an idol is such a pain!!
どうした、藪から棒に
What's wrong? That's so out of the blue.
気にしないでください。いつもの発作です。
Please don't mind her. It's just her usual fit.
だって吾輩、悪の秘密結社の総帥だよ?
I mean, I'm the leader of an evil secret society, you know?
なのになんでアイドルなんかやらなきゃいけないの?
So why on earth do I have to do something like being an idol?
真逆じゃん! 真逆のイメージじゃんかよー!
It's the complete opposite! It's the total opposite image!
どうしたでござるか?
Is something wrong?
ルイとかはいいよ、うん
Lui and the others are fine, yeah...
おーい、沙花叉どうした?
Hey, Sakamata, what's wrong?
吾輩もう疲れたの
I'm already tired of this.
そもそもアイドルやってくださいって言われたの?
Wait, were you even asked to be an idol in the first place?
はぁ? 言われてないんかい!!
Huh? You weren't even asked!?
言われてなかった...
I wasn't asked...
ってことは吾輩、勝手にアイドルやってた人ってこと?
Does that mean I've just been being an idol on my own this whole time?
いや、でもバズってたよね、あれ
Well, but that video did go viral, didn't it?
バズるってことは、たくさんの人に知ってもらえることになるし
Going viral means a lot of people will get to know you.
それすなわち、世界征服では?
And wouldn't that mean... world domination?
それそれ!
Exactly!
確かに...
Certainly...
見なよ、ホロライブ先輩のオーラ見てよ
Look, look at the aura of the Hololive senpais.
すっごいきらきらだね
It's so sparkly!
これぞアイドルって感じですね
This really feels like what an idol should be.
可愛いでござる!
It's so cute!
いや、てか、あの、なんか...
No, I mean, well, somehow...
ここにいる人は、みんなきらきらしてるんだけどさ
Everyone here is so sparkly, but...
ラプラスのオーラって、なんか...
Laplus's aura is kind of...
禍々しい...
Ominous...
言われなくても分かってるんだよ!
I know that without you telling me!
吾輩だって、せっかくそろそろ2周年ライブがあるのに!
Even I... and the 2nd anniversary live is finally almost here!
しょうがないな〜
Well, I guess we have no choice.
やったりましょう!
Let's do this!
せっかちだなぁ
How impatient.
みんなもいいよね?
Everyone else is okay with it too, right?
題して! ラプラス・ダークネス アイドル昇華大作戦、決行!
Titled! The La+ Darknesss Idol Sublimation Grand Plan, commence!
ええええ〜!
Eeeeeee?!
Signalize!
作詞：わかばやし
作曲・編曲：NARASAKI
編曲：SADESPER RECORD
Lyrics: Wakabayashi
Composition/Arrangement: NARASAKI
Arrangement: SADESPER RECORD
Signalize! 答えは もっと
Signalize! The answer is further
高い空の彼方
away in the high sky
いいえ違うよ 僕の
No, that's not it, I could see
目にも見えた 地の果て
the edge of the earth too
Signalize! 激しく なった
Signalize! The hot power in my heart
胸の熱いパワー
has become intense
そうだ漲る 何かが
That's right, something is overflowing
だから今を信じて
so believe in the now
始めよう
Let's begin
ただの憧れじゃいちゃダメ
just longing is not enough
残酷な夢が 夢で 夢になるんだ
A cruel dream becomes a dream within a dream
ほら挑戦待ってるよ
look, a challenge is waiting
君と 向かう場所はどこだろう
Where is the place I'm heading with you?
眩しい希望の中へ
Into the dazzling hope
望む場所はどこだろう
Where is the place we desire?
探しに行こうよ 淑女（しゅくじょ）のスタンス
Let's go find it, with a lady's poise
向かう場所は 未来の
The place we're heading is
僕らの 希望の中に
in our future hope
望む場所は 未来の
The place we desire is
輝きが 合図 Let’s go-go!
where brilliance is the signal, Let’s go-go!
Signalize! 例えば 今日は
Signalize! For example, today
青い迷路だった
was a blue maze
早く抜け出せ 僕と
Escape quickly, just come
来ればいいさ このまま
with me as you are
Signalize! 光の ように
Signalize! A sudden energy
走る不意のエネルギー
running like light
震えるほどの 奇跡を
A miracle so great it makes you tremble
だから今は信じて
so believe in the now
叶えたい
I want to fulfill it
強く願い続ける力
the power to keep wishing strongly
純粋な歌を 歌え 歌いたいんだ
Sing a pure song, I want to sing
もう絶望なんてしない
I won't despair anymore
やがて 生まれ変わる世界を
Into the premonition of feeling
感じる予感の中へ
the world that will be reborn
移り変わる世界を
It's a journey seeking
求める旅路だ 前進だ
the changing world, move forward
生まれ変わるメロディ
The melody that's reborn
僕らは希望の中さ
we are in the midst of hope
やっと変わるメロディ
The melody finally changing
煌めいた地図で It’s new world!
with a sparkling map, It’s new world!
Signalize!
Do you know?
Believe now!
向かう場所はどこだろう
Where is the place I'm heading?
眩しい希望の中へ
Into the dazzling hope
望む場所はどこだろう
Where is the place we desire?
探しに行こうよ 淑女（しゅくじょ）のスタンス
Let's go find it, with a lady's poise
向かう場所は 未来の
The place we're heading is
僕らの 希望の中に
in our future hope
望む場所は 未来の
The place we desire is
輝きが 合図 Let’s go-go!
where brilliance is the signal, Let’s go-go!
Signalize!
Do you know?
Believe now!
夕映えプレゼント
作詞：遠藤フビト 作曲：BNSI (Yoshi)
編曲：BNSI (Yoshi) / 滝澤俊輔 (TRYTONELABO)
Yuubae Present
Lyrics: Fubito Endo Composition: BNSI (Yoshi)
Arrangement: BNSI (Yoshi) / Shunsuke Takizawa (TRYTONELABO)
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうな
It's so beautiful it's like a dream, it makes me want to cry
明るい空　見つけたひとすじの流れ星
In the bright sky, I found a single shooting star
黄昏に　染まる世界が好き
I love the world dyed in twilight
素敵な出来事を　集めるのが好き
I love collecting wonderful events
誰といようと　一つの物語
Whoever I'm with, it's a single story
自分らしく歩くの　いつでも始められるよ
I can start walking as myself anytime
ほら　溢れる夕焼けは
Look, the overflowing sunset is
優しい光のプレゼント
A gift of gentle light
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうな
It's so beautiful it's like a dream, it makes me want to cry
これからたくさんいいことあるよ
Many good things are going to happen from now on
もし手を伸ばしたら届くかな
I wonder if it will reach if I stretch out my hand
明るい空　見つけたひとすじの流れ星
In the bright sky, I found a single shooting star
柔らかい　香りの部屋が好き
I love a room with a soft scent
楽しい思い出を　数えるのが好き
I love counting happy memories
悩みとか　迷いもあるけれど
There are worries and hesitations, but
覗く顔変えたら　いつでも元気になれるよ
If I change the face I show, I can always be energetic
ほら　寂しくないからね
Look, I'm not lonely, you know
眩しい光のモニュメント
A monument of dazzling light
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうな
It's so beautiful it's like a dream, it makes me want to cry
これから何度もいいことあるよ
Many good things will happen again and again
伸びる影帽子　見送る風
Stretching shadows, the wind that sees us off
明るい空　見上げてまた一筋流れ星
Looking up at the bright sky, another shooting star
例えば　魔法が使えたらね
If, for example, I could use magic
ベルトの羽根を　背中に貼り付けて
I'd attach belt wings to my back
雲の切れ間から　飛び出すよ
And jump out from between the clouds
みんなの心、笑っちゃうよ！
Everyone's hearts will be smiling!
これからずっとだよ！
From now on, forever!
大切な存在に、みんなが幸せになりますように！
To all the precious ones, may you all be happy!
最高の思い出にしようね！
Let's make this the best memory ever!
みんなの気持ち、待ってるよ！
I'm waiting for all your feelings!
2周年、最高のプレゼント、ありがとう！
2nd anniversary, thank you for the best present!
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうよ
It's so beautiful it's like a dream, it makes me want to cry
明日も明後日も　その次の日も
Tomorrow, the day after, and the day after that too
素敵な出来事の花束を
A bouquet of wonderful events
両手に抱いて　駆け出す夕暮れの街角
Holding it in both hands, I run out into the street corner at dusk
もし手を伸ばしたら触れるかな
I wonder if I can touch it if I stretch out my hand
空に舞いて　こぼれた幸せの花びら　夢吹き色
Dancing in the sky, spilled petals of happiness, in the color of a dream breeze
Dive to Blue
作詞・作曲・編曲：玉屋2060%
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Tamaya 2060%
みんなー！今日、吾輩の2周年ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you for coming to my 2nd anniversary live today!
そして今日は一年の、一番吾輩がアイドルの日！
And today is the day of the year when I am the most of an idol!
絶対、絶対最強の一日にするので、みんな最後まで見ていってくれ！
I'll definitely, definitely make it the strongest day ever, so please stay until the end!
そして、次に披露する曲は「Dive to Blue」！いくぞー！
And the next song I'll perform is "Dive to Blue"! Here we go!
マリンブルー 深い溜息 溶かしたフューチャー・パーティー
Marine blue, deep sighs dissolved into a future party
出会いと連なり 愛と後悔 巡る心模様
Meetings and sequences, love and regret, a circulating landscape of the heart
季節が終わり カレンダーをめくったら
When the season ends and I turn the calendar page
明日がちょっと 怖くなって 不意に立ち止まる
I get a little scared of tomorrow and suddenly stop
君に会えたら 伝えたいことがあるんだ
If I could meet you, there's something I'd want to tell you
海の青さや 眩しさや 君の優しさ
The blue of the sea, the brightness, and your kindness
吹き抜ける風に 種をまいたら
If I sow seeds in the breeze that blows through
心の闇を裂いて 君を迎えに行くよ
I'll tear through the darkness of my heart and go to meet you
Surf! let me dive into sky 潜ったらユートピア
Surf! let me dive into sky, once I dive, it's Utopia
波に溶けて 超高速のスピードでもっと
Dissolving in the waves, even more at ultra-high speed
Surf! Backing, backing down 君が壊して呼び覚ます
Surf! Backing, backing down, you break and awaken it
この果てない海原に君の手を捕って飛び込むよ
Into this endless ocean, I'll take your hand and dive
みんな！ まだまだいけるよな！？
Everyone! You can still go on, right?!
今日は波に溶けちゃうくらい最高の夜にするから！
I'll make it a night so great you'll dissolve in the waves!
まだまだいくぞー！
Let's keep going!
ノスタルジー 鼓動を解いて遠くまで
Nostalgia, unbinding the heartbeat and going far away
流した涙は 光となって やがて降り注ぐ
The tears shed turn into light and eventually pour down
君にいつかは 見せたい景色があるんだ
There's a scene I want to show you someday
空の広さや 輝きや 君の美しさ
The vastness of the sky, the brilliance, and your beauty
遠ざかる昨日 まだ見ぬ明日
The receding yesterday, the tomorrow yet unseen
溺れそうな今 抱きしめて 君を迎えに行くよ
Embracing the now that feels like drowning, I'll go to meet you
Surf! let me dive into sky 届いたらユートピア
Surf! let me dive into sky, once it reaches, it's Utopia
通り過ぎてった日々も思い出スローモーション
The passing days too, are memories in slow motion
Surf! Backing, backing down 手を振ってサヨナラ・ディストピア
Surf! Backing, backing down, wave goodbye to dystopia
満ちあふれた未来に君の手を捕って飛び込むよ
I'll take your hand and dive into the overflowing future
さあ、一緒に！
Come on, together!
手を繋いで！
Holding hands!
そしたらもう、怖くないよ
Then, we won't be afraid anymore
悩んだり迷ったり巡り巡って
Worrying, getting lost, going round and round
もどかしさの中で遠ざかっていく
Receding within the frustration
あの日の悲しみ 喜びが全部
The sadness and joy of that day, all of it
君になっていくんだ さあ手を伸ばして
Turns into you, now reach out your hand
Surf! let me dive into sky 潜ったらユートピア
Surf! let me dive into sky, once I dive, it's Utopia
波に溶けて 超高速のスピードでもっと
Dissolving in the waves, even more at ultra-high speed
Surf! Backing, backing down 君が壊して呼び覚ます
Surf! Backing, backing down, you break and awaken it
この果てない海原に君の手を捕って飛び込むよ
Into this endless ocean, I'll take your hand and dive
Blue sky, let me dive, into my utopia
Blue sky...
キライキライ言ったって本心じゃない
Even if I say I hate it, it's not my true feeling
小悪魔的なテクニック
A little devilish technique
クライクライ泣いたって心配はない
Even if I cry cry, there's no need to worry
涙さえ武器にするの
I'll even make tears my weapon
ドキドキキラビリンス
Doki Doki Kirabirinsu
作詞・作曲・編曲：Haggy Rock
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Haggy Rock
誰かを思いながら夜を眠るの
Falling asleep at night while thinking of someone
君の夢にお邪魔したい
I want to visit your dreams
たまに視線感じはするけど
Sometimes I feel a gaze, though
ちゃんと私だけ見ててよ
Make sure you're only looking at me
会いたい 隣にいたい
I want to meet you, I want to be next to you
この気持ちは変わらない
This feeling won't change
君の笑顔 君の優しさ
Your smile, your kindness
見せつけて
Show it to me
したいしたい 恋心 進展して
I want to, I want to, let my feelings of love progress
クライ クライ クライ いつだって心配はない
Cry, cry, cry, there's never any worry.
涙さえ武器になる
Even tears become a weapon.
トライ トライ トライ いつだって頂点じゃん
Try, try, try, I'm always at the top.
結末は分からない
I don't know the ending.
ドキドキのラビリンス
A heart-pounding labyrinth.
他の子たちと喋ってるところ
Seeing you talking with other girls...
見たらしいっとしてちゃうかな
...I think I might get a bit jealous.
大体シンパ脳 逃しちゃうかもよ
I might lose my common sense.
モヤモヤしないでお願い
Please don't be so restless.
嘘ついたりより合ったり
Lying, getting closer to each other.
臆病風は止まない
The wind of cowardice won't stop.
恋は仕方ないやつ使いは
Love is such a helpless thing.
気を付けて
Be careful.
クライ クライ クライ いつだって本心じゃない
Cry, cry, cry, it's not always my true heart.
小悪魔になってくテクニック
Techniques to become a little devil.
クライ クライ クライ いつだって心配はない
Cry, cry, cry, there's never any worry.
涙さえ武器になる
Even tears become a weapon.
ドキドキのスパイラル
A heart-pounding spiral.
グッドで恋はスパイラル
With 'good', love is a spiral.
グッドで心踊りだす
With 'good', my heart starts dancing.
バッドでたまに空回り
With 'bad', sometimes I spin my wheels.
バッドで信じていたい
With 'bad', I still want to believe.
足りない足りない努力の日々
Never enough, never enough days of effort.
負けない負けない躓いても
Won't give up, won't give up even if I stumble.
ドキドキのモチベはいつでも
My heart-pounding motivation is always...
君だから
...because of you.
誰を想いながら夜を眠るの
Who do you think of as you sleep at night?
君の夢にお邪魔したい
I want to pay a visit to your dreams.
恋 恋 恋 本当は無理して
Love, love, love, honestly I'm pushing myself...
強気な子演じてる
...to act like a tough girl.
辛い 辛い 辛い ばか痛いくらい
Painful, painful, painful, it hurts so much.
プライドでサバイバル
Survival through my pride.
トライ トライ トライ ばか進展がない
Try, try, try, there's no progress at all.
モヤモヤが溜まってく
The restlessness keeps building up.
トライ トライ トライ いつだって挑戦じゃん
Try, try, try, it's always a challenge.
結末は分からない
I don't know the ending.
ドキドキのラビリンス
A heart-pounding labyrinth.
貴様ら集合！
You lots, assemble!
はーい！
Yeah!
はい、ということで！
Yes, and so!
ライブです！
It's a live!
おーい！
Oi!
やったー！
Yippee!
お前ら！吾輩がお前らのより先に2周年になった！
You guys! I've reached my 2nd anniversary before all of you!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
ちょっと待って！
Wait a minute!
ちょ、ちょっと待って！
Wait, wait a minute!
お金ないっすよ！
We don't have any money!
許してください！
Please forgive us!
黙れ！うるさいうるさい！
Shut up! Shush, shush!
ということで、吾輩が一番最初にライブやって...
And so, I'm the first one doing a live...
一番先輩なんですけど！
I'm the most senior after all!
だるい
So annoying.
で、次は？
And next?
お！ルイさんのライブが明日あります！
Oh! Lui-san's live is tomorrow!
ポンコツ幹部ルイのライブです！
It's the Ponkotsu Executive Lui's live!
よかったら見に来てください！見に来てくれるかなー？
Please come see it if you like! I wonder if you'll come see it?
いいるいー！
Ee Lui!
いいのかなこれ！？
Is this really okay!?
じゃあ、次は？
Then, next?
はーい！こよりです！明後日ライブだよ！
Yes! It's Koyori! The day after tomorrow is my live!
見に来てくれるかなー？
I wonder if you'll come see it?
いいこよー！
Ee Koyo!
やめてー！
Stop it!
次は？
Next?
はい！坂又です！坂又もやりますんで、よろしくお願いします！
Yes! It's Sakamata! Sakamata will be doing one too, so please look forward to it!
見に来てくれるかなー！？
I wonder if you'll come see it!?
いいさかー！
Ee Saka!
最後は？
And lastly?
はい！最後はござる！ござるでござる！
Yes! Lastly is Gozaru! It's Gozaru de gozaru!
ござるもやるでござる！皆見に来てくれるでござるかー？
Gozaru will be doing one too de gozaru! Will everyone come see me de gozaru?
いいござー！
Ee Goza!
はい、ということで！そして全員の2周年ライブがバァーッと終わったら...
Yes, so! And after everyone's 2nd anniversary lives are all over...
お、終わったら？
O-Once they're over?
何があるんですか？
What happens then?
holoXの2周年ライブもやります！
We'll also have a holoX 2nd anniversary live!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いやー、今年は参加できますからね。
Man, I can actually participate this year.
あ、そうだ！
Ah, that's right!
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
喉がいい感じなんですよ、最近。
My throat's been feeling great lately.
よかったよかった！元気でいてくれよ！
Good, good! Stay healthy!
元気でいるぞ！
I'll stay healthy!
ということで！はい！この曲どうだった？吾輩、アイドルだった？
So! Yes! How was that song? Was I an idol?
おー、意外とアイドルだった。可愛い！
Oh, you were surprisingly idol-like. Cute!
勝ったねー！
We won!
最高だったー！
That was the best!
ハート作って！
Make a heart!
ウインクめっちゃ良かったよ。
Your wink was really good.
Ｌ・Ｄ・Ｓ！
L-D-S!
あーいいね。ありがとうございます。
Ah, nice. Thank you very much.
普段とのギャップがね、良かった。
The gap from your usual self was great.
ね！ラプラス・ダークネスさんだった。
Right! You were La+ Darknesss-san.
おいおいおい、ちゃんと可愛いからね！
Hey hey hey, I'm properly cute, you know!
なんか良かったよ、ラプラス・アイドルネスちゃん。
That was somehow good, La+ Idolnesss-chan.
あ、うん。あの、吾輩のことちゃん呼びしていいのは、こよりだけなんだ！
Ah, yeah. Um, only Koyori is allowed to call me "chan"!
ラプちゃーん！ラプちゃーん！
Lap-chan! Lap-chan!
やめろー！やめろ！吾輩のことラプちゃんって呼ばないでください！
Stop it! Stop! Please don't call me Lap-chan!
ラプちゃーん！ラプちゃーん！
Lap-chan! Lap-chan!
こよクロはダメです！解散してまーす！
Koyo-Chloe is no good! We're disbanding!
でも！でも！なんか吾輩、足りない要素がある気がするんだよな。
But! But! I feel like there's some element I'm missing.
え、そう？別に今でもいいんじゃない？
Eh, really? Isn't it fine as you are now?
ちょっとね、満足したよね、今の。
Yeah, I was satisfied with that just now.
いいよいいよ、このままで。
It's fine, it's fine, just like this.
足りないものがあるはずなの！
There must be something missing!
身長とかじゃない？
Maybe it's height?
おま、黙れ！アイドルとしてってこと！
You, shut up! I mean as an idol!
そうだよ。じゃあ、アイドルについて詳しそうな人のところに行ってみる？
That's right. Then, shall we go see someone who seems to know a lot about idols?
お、行こう行こう！いいね、行こう！
Oh, let's go, let's go! Sounds good, let's go!
行こう！アイドルさんに会いに行こう！
Let's go! Let's go meet some idols!
行こう行こう！バイバーイ！
Let's go, let's go! Bye-bye!
このライブのアイドル、清楚担当といえば！
When you think of the pure idol of this live!
いえば……？
If you say...?
本気で言ってんの？ねえ、みんな！
Are you saying that seriously? Hey, everyone!
この人は「ドカ」とか「ドカ」とか普通に言うのに！
Even though this person normally says crude things!
え、ラプちゃん「ドカ」って言わないの？
Eh, Lap-chan doesn't say crude things?
「ドカ」って言わねーよ！
I don't say that!
言ってるねー。
You're saying it.
これは言ったなー。
She definitely said it.
だー！はめられたー！
Gah! I've been set up!
自分から言ってたけどなー。
You were saying it yourself though.
言ってたねー。
You were saying it.
まあ、でも……。
Well, but...
ライブの時とか、いざという時に「ジャン！」って決めるアイドルってかっこよくない？
Isn't an idol who nails it when it counts, like during a live, cool?
まあ、尊敬はしてるけどね。
Well, I do respect them.
えー！ラプラス、スバルのこと尊敬してんの！？
Eh! La+, you respect Subaru!?
尊敬とか……尊敬とか……。
Respect... Respect...
おい、スバル様、お前尊敬してねーだろう、こいつ！
Hey, Subaru-sama, this guy doesn't respect you at all!
まつりさん、キュート
Matsuri-san, Cute
吾輩、まつりさん……キュート。え、まつりキュート？
Me, Matsuri-san... Cute. Eh, Matsuri is cute?
わためさん、クール
Watame-san, Cool
わためさん……クール。
Watame-san... Cool.
わための歌、かっこいいでしょう。
Watame's singing is cool, isn't it?
スバル、パッション
Subaru, Passion
パッションってなんだ！
What's "Passion"!
スバル先輩のパフォーマンスは、見ていて元気がもらえますよね。
You can get energy just from watching Subaru-senpai's performance.
うんうん！
Yeah, yeah!
は！これだ！
Hah! This is it!
この三つの要素が揃えば、吾輩は完璧で究極のアイドル！
If these three elements are all here, I'll be the perfect and ultimate idol!
ラプちゃんに今足りない要素って何かな？
I wonder what elements Lap-chan is missing now?
ガキだからクールさはないよな。
Since she's a brat, she has no coolness.
キュートって感じでもないよね。
She doesn't really feel cute either.
オーラはパッションというか、どすぐろい感じ。
Her aura is less "passion" and more like "dark and murky".
おい、全部足りねーじゃねーか！ふざけんなよ！
Hey, so I'm missing everything! Don't mess with me!
かくなる上は……出でよ！助っ斗ボタン！
In that case... Come forth! Helper Button!
どこからー！？
From where!?
こよりが作りました。
Koyori made it.
なんでもありだ。
Anything goes.
このボタンで助っ斗を呼び出し、足りない要素を補ってやるぞ！
I'll call forth helpers with this button and supplement the missing elements!
誰を呼ぶつもりなのかな？
I wonder who you're planning to call?
それは押してからのお楽しみだよね！
That's something to look forward to after I press it!
えい！
Ei!
Yeah!
From the bottom!
Woo... ha...
さんざっぱら！ＨＡ！
Sanzappara! HA!
空き札に！ＨＡ！
To the empty tag! HA!
三人で！
The three of us!
劣等上等お待たせ校舎　いまテイクオフ！
Bring It On, the long-awaited school building, taking off now!
Hey! Hey! 劣等上等　Bring it on
Hey! Hey! Bring It On, Bring it on
子供騙しのマセマティカ
Child's play mathematics
摩天楼すらも　グッバイとおさらば
Even skyscrapers, goodbye and farewell
虎視眈々　狙う獲物
Vigilantly watching the prey
中身のねえ　ツラばかりでつまんねえ
Just empty faces, it's boring
Is funny?
ほら　もっと　ぶちかましてよ
Come on, let 'em have it more
退屈に手を掛けて
Put a hand on the boredom
ママ　やっぱ　私は
Mama, as I thought, I...
こんな所じゃ終われない
Can't end in a place like this
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I'm going crazy
ごっこ遊びも失敗もサヨナラ
Farewell to playing pretend and failures
ずっとこのままなんてさ
Just staying like this forever...
いらないよ
I don't need that
ダッダッダ　あたし大人になる
Da da da, I'm going to become an adult
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Experiencing both the bitter and the sweet now
パッパッパ　変わる時代
Pa pa pa, the changing era
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
Isn't it not just bad things?
過去も罪も罰もすべて
The past, the sins, the punishments, everything
素手で愛でて生き抜いてやる
I'll cherish them with bare hands and survive
勝ち誇れ
Be triumphant
Oh Yeah! Oh Yeah!
ＨＡ！
HA!
挑発　アタシ達はＮＯ
Provocation, we are a NO
緑のあいつにバチコーンかましてね
Give that green one a solid smack
三番勝負の果てに貰える合格
A passing grade received at the end of a three-round match
赤ペン入れちゃって　どこがダメなんですか
Put in red ink, where is it no good?
酒を酌み交わしちゃってコンプラ
Drinking together, compliance
知るってハァーイ？
Knowing, ha-i?
冗談じゃん　ブラックジョーク
Just a joke, a black joke
笑えない
Can't laugh
劣等上等
Bring It On
なびいた同じ愛しすぎて指が足んねえからハンズアップ
I loved it so much that I didn't have enough fingers, so hands up
1, 2, 3 で 待って 最低
1, 2, 3, wait, the worst
元々だ 凛々々等
It's always been that way, Ri-Ri-Ri-...
ダッダッダッ くだらない
Da da da, how trivial
欲しがります死ぬまでは
I'll keep wanting until I die
うーん...
Uun...
伸ばせた背伸び そっと街に投げキッス
I've grown taller, blowing a kiss to the city
見せ場はこっから 覚悟しとけよ
The show starts now, so get ready
ダッダッダッ 僕らも どんなになるか
Da da da, what will become of us?
三三三 狙い いたいけな君に
1, 2, 3, aiming for the innocent you
ダッダッダッ ぶちかまし 人生 嫌われ者
Da da da, slamming through life, the outcast
五・六・七・八 咲き誇れよ
5, 6, 7, 8, bloom in full glory!
愛想でしょ？
It's just politeness, right?
ぶっ飛ばすぞ すべて
I'll blow it all away
すべてのすべて
Every last bit of it
生きて 痛いって
Living, saying it hurts
覆してゆこう
Let's turn it all around
Love & Hate ひねりないだろ？
Love & Hate, no twist there, right?
わらわも一緒に歌おう！
Let's sing together!
なんかやるんじゃないの？
Aren't we gonna do something?
なんで笑ってるの！？
Why are you laughing!?
ヒメちゃん！ヒナちゃん！かっこよく行こうぜ！
Hime-chan! Hina-chan! Let's go cool!
行こうぜ！
Let's go!
ダッダッダッ くだらない
Da da da, how trivial
言葉ばかり 譲れない
Just words, I won't back down
わかるか？ あたしの美学
Do you understand? My aesthetic
この馬鹿正直な
This foolishly honest...
拳ひとつが 切り札
Single fist is my trump card
悪食なんて 我鳴る 劣等
Gormandizing, my roaring inferiority
一抜けろ さらば
Get out first, farewell
こんなもんじゃない！
It's not just this!
ダッダッダッ 私も どんなになるか
Da da da, what will I become?
酸いも甘いも 噛み分けて今
Experienced in both the bitter and the sweet, now...
惨憺 私 悪い未来も
Miserable me, even a bad future...
この手で 咲かせるでしょう？
...I'll make it bloom with these hands, right?
待って 光
Wait, light
船出の合図
The signal to set sail
見てて 生き抜け
Watch me survive
ちょっと上等
A little superior
愛ある人生だ
It's a life full of love
それでは皆様、お先にバイバイ
Well then everyone, bye-bye for now
フロアが湧き上がりました
The floor is pumped up
劣等上等
Bring It On
わー！
Wow!
ヒメヒナさん、来てくれてありがとうございます！
HimeHina-san, thank you for coming!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
来てくれたー！
We're here!
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
はい！
Okay!
行くよ！
Here we go!
せーの！
Ready, go!
ほう、田中ヒメです！
Hou, I'm Tanaka Hime!
鈴木ヒナです！
I'm Suzuki Hina!
お邪魔します！
Pleased to be here!
本物だ！やったー、本物だ！
The real deal! Yay, it's really them!
いやー嬉しい！ねー、呼んでくれて嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy! We're so glad you invited us!
こんなところで一緒に歌えて嬉しい！
I'm so happy we could sing together like this!
いやー、遠くまでわざわざありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming all this way!
いやいやいや、こちらこそ！
No, no, the pleasure is ours!
やったー！もうあとコラボとかね、歌ってみたでも...
Yay! And with our collabs and 'Utattemita' covers...
うんうん、いっぱい呼んでいただきまして...
Yeah, you've invited us many times...
嬉しかったんですけど、今日、ここまで来ていただいて...
I was so happy, but for you to come here today...
いや、どこでも行くよ！ついて行くよ！
We'll go anywhere! We'll follow you!
嬉しい、ありがとうございます！
I'm so glad, thank you!
さあそれでは、この3人と言えば...
Well then, speaking of the three of us...
まずは生放送に来てもらって、そのあとね、歌コラボで...
First you came to my stream, and then, our song collab...
あ、もう出てるね！
Oh, it's already on screen!
マトリョシカ
Matryoshika
マトリョシカ歌いました！
We sang Matryoshika!
イェーイ！我々のチャンネルに上がってるんだよね！
Yay! It's up on our channel, right!
そう！みんな聴いてください！
Yes! Everyone, please listen to it!
やっぱりお二人、めっちゃ歌上手くて...
As expected, you two are amazing singers...
えー、嬉しい！
Aww, thank you!
先にお二人が収録されたのを聞きながら私も歌ったんですけど、
I sang while listening to the parts you recorded first,
もう、上手っ！ってなって...
And I was like, 'They're so good!'...
もうセクシーボイス凄くて...
Your sexy voice was incredible...
そう、かっこいいんだよ！
Yeah, it was so cool!
そうなんですよ、ありがとうございます！
I know, right? Thank you!
大好きだよ！
I love you!
ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
ヒナさんは？
What about Hina-san?
なに、なに？大好き大好きおばさんになって...
What, what? I'm becoming an 'I love you' lady...
いやもう世界一大好きだわ！
No, I love you the most in the world!
いやでもお二人が一番ね、仲良しですから...
But you two are the best of friends...
間に入るなんてちょっと...
For me to get in between you two is...
いいよいいよ、入っちゃえ入っちゃえ！
It's fine, it's fine! Just jump right in!
ありがとうございます、元気だね！
Thank you, you're so energetic!
本当に、今回 劣等上等 歌ったんですけど、
Seriously, we sang 'Bring It On' this time,
いやめちゃ歌いながら踊るのやばいっすね！
But dancing while singing is crazy!
やばい、みんなちょっと疲れ気味で...
It's crazy, everyone's a bit exhausted...
でも元気にいっぱいダンスしちゃったんですけど...
But we did a lot of energetic dancing...
いやでも、ついにやらせていただいたんですけど、やっぱりお二人のがかっこよすぎて！
But even though we finally did it, you two were just too cool!
えー嬉しい！
Aww, thank you!
お二人の 劣等上等 聞いてこの曲覚えたんで！
I learned this song by listening to your version!
えー！そうなの！？
Whoa! Really!?
恐れ多いです！
I'm humbled!
本当だね、大先輩ですからね！
True, you're such a great senior!
いやーもう、下がって下がって...
No way, I should bow down...
前、後ろ行ってるよ、どうぞどうぞ！
Front, back, you're going everywhere, go ahead!
もう後ろ、階段登っちゃうよ
I'm gonna end up climbing the stairs at the back!
嬉しい、ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy, thank you!
劣等上等さ、こうやってコラボで歌ったこと初めてだよね多分！
This is probably the first time we've sung 'Bring It On' as a collab!
そうだ、初めてだ！
That's right, it's the first time!
ねー、レア回！一緒にコラボ嬉しい！
Yeah, a rare occasion! I'm so happy for this collab!
嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
I'm happy too! Thank you!
初めて！
First time!
やったーみんなー！
We did it, everyone!
フー！
Whoo!
盛り上がっております！
Things are heating up!
今コメント欄も「うわーっ」てなってたよね？
The comment section was going wild just now, right?
ね、ありがとう！
Yeah, thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
や、ね。
Yeah, really.
はい、でもまた、ね、またコラボしたい！
Yes, but also, you know, I want to collab again!
したい、したい！
I want to, I want to!
いやいや、今回はちょっとかっこいい系の曲を連発で爆走したんで。
No no, since we just ran through a series of cool songs this time...
次は、ちょっと次は楽しいのとかやりたい！
Next, I want to do something fun!
えー！いい！
Oh! That sounds good!
いい、ハッピー系？ハッピー系？
Nice, like something happy? Happy-style?
とりあえずヒメヒナさん可愛いというか、キュートっぽい感じの曲を歌ってる印象があんまりなくて、やっぱクールの...
Basically, I don't really have an image of HimeHina singing cute songs; it's always cool...
ああ、我々そう、アーティストだから。
Ah, that's right, because we're artists.
そうですね、アーティストだから。
Exactly, because we're artists.
普段はちょっとこういう感じなんですけど。
We're usually like this, but...
歌って踊る姿めちゃめちゃかっこいいんで。
The way you sing and dance is super cool.
うれしい！
That makes us happy!
ちょっとね、こういう感じ、日常っぽい感じ？の歌とかやりたい。
I want to try a song with this kind of everyday feel.
やろう！
Let's do it!
やりたい！
I want to!
やったー！コラボ決まったぞー！
Yay! The collab is decided!
すでに！やったー！
Already! Yay!
みんな覚えといてね！言質取ったからね！
Everyone, remember this! We've got it on record!
やばい、言質取られた！
Oh no, I've been held to my word!
言質ですよ！
You're on record!
ライブで言質取りましたけど！
We've got your word here at the live show!
言質、言質。
On record, on record.
まあじゃあクールはもうマスターしたということで。
Well then, let's say we've mastered the cool style.
いやもうお二人のおかげで、マスターしましたよ！
No, thanks to you two, I've mastered it!
おー！やったー！
Oh! Yay!
マスターしました！
Mastered it!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
次の場所も頑張りますんで。
I'll do my best at the next place too.
なに？頑張って！頑張ってねー！
What? Do your best! Good luck!
じゃあもう頑張って、アイドル目指して頑張ってね！
Well then, keep going, do your best aiming to be an idol!
いやーもうヒメヒナさんありがとう！バイバーイ！
Ah, thank you HimeHina! Bye bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye bye!
ありがとうございましたー！バイバーイ！
Thank you very much! Bye bye!
あ、一緒に行こう。
Ah, let's go together.
誰もいなくなっちゃう。
Everyone will be gone.
Mela!
作詞：長屋晴子 / 小林壱誓 作曲：peppe / 穴見真吾
Lyrics: Haruko Nagaya / Issei Kobayashi  Composition: peppe / Shingo Anami
今なんじゃない？ メラメラと滾る
Isn't now the time? Blazing and boiling over
眠っているだけの正義
Justice that's only been sleeping
こんな僕も 君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero
LALALA...
かっこいい君には 僕じゃ頼りないのかなんて
I wonder if I'm too unreliable for a cool person like you
そりゃそうだよね だって 今もこうして迷ってる
That's true, isn't it? Because even now I'm lost like this
LALALA... 手を取ってくれないか
LALALA... Won't you take my hand?
LALALA... ギブとテイクさ
LALALA... It's give and take
LALALA... 君が僕のヒーローだったように
LALALA... Just like you were my hero
今なんじゃない？ メラメラと滾る
Isn't now the time? Blazing and boiling over
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice lurking even inside someone like me
どうしようもない 衝動に駆られて
Being driven by an uncontrollable impulse
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, before I know it, I'm holding your hand
いったいぜんたい そんなに荷物を
What on earth are you doing with so much luggage?
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going carrying all that?
ねえねえ待って 僕にちょっと預けてみては
Hey, hey, wait, why not try entrusting it to me for a bit?
信じてばかりの僕と 信じることが怖い君と
Me who only ever believes, and you who are afraid to believe
どちらが正しいのかなんて 誰にも分からないさ
No one knows which of us is right
LALALA... 僕らだけの世界
LALALA... A world only for us
LALALA... ギブとテイクさ
LALALA... It's give and take
LALALA... 補い合えたその先には
LALALA... Beyond where we could complement each other
同じ夢を見たい
I want to see the same dream
君は葛藤と 苦しんで 独りぼっちに
You're struggling with conflict, all alone
させたのは少し僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
I'm a little bit to blame for that, aren't I? I'm sorry
だけど見るべきは リアルだ 今こそ僕が助ける番だ
But what you should look at is reality, now it's my turn to help
抱えないで 信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't hold it all in, I want you to believe in me and rely on me
今なんじゃない？ メラメラと滾る
Isn't now the time? Blazing and boiling over
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice lurking even inside someone like me
どうしようもない 衝動に駆られて
Being driven by an uncontrollable impulse
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, before I know it, I'm holding your hand
放っておけない そんなに荷物を
I can't just leave you alone, with so much luggage...
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going carrying all that?
ほんのちょっと 僕にちょっと預けてみては
Just a little bit, why not try entrusting it to me for a bit?
こんな僕も 君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero
LA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA...
わあー！いたいたいた！
Waa! There they are!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
いぇーい！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
ちょこらから自己紹介お願いします！
Choco-ra, please introduce yourself!
はい！癒月ちょこです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! I'm Yuzuki Choco! Nice to meet you!
次！
Next!
はい、獅白ぼたんです。お願いします！
Yes, I'm Shishiro Botan. Nice to meet you!
いぇーい！
Yay!
いや、いつぶりですか？
Man, how long has it been?
えっ、なんで忘れてんだよ！
Eh, why did you forget?!
V最以来だろ！
It's since V-sa-I!
あ、そうでした、そうでした！
Ah, right, right!
いや懐かしいよ、半年以上前ということで。
How nostalgic, it's been over half a year.
はい、お久しぶりですね。
Yes, it's been a while.
お久しぶりです！お久しぶりです！
It's been a while! It's been a while!
あの時は誘ってくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you for inviting me back then.
いや本当に、みんなでね、お世話になりました！
No, really, thank you everyone for your help!
嬉しかったよ、誘ってくれて。
I was happy you invited me.
今日はお二人、我が誘って集めたんで。
I was the one who invited and gathered you two today.
次は、僕が…
Next is... me?
えっ？なに？次は？なんなんですか？
Eh? What? Next? What is it?
ファンの皆もEMAどんな形でもいいから見たい、みたいなことすごい言ってたんで。
The fans were saying they wanted to see EMA in any form...
ちょっと良いことした、良いことしました！ありがとうございます！
So I did something good! Thank you!
『Mela!』を今回歌って踊ったんですけど、どうでしたか？
We sang and danced to 'Mela!' this time. How was it?
めちゃ難しかった！！
It was really difficult!!
歌苦手って言ってたのに、すごい練習してくれて。
Even though she said she's bad at singing, she practiced so much.
ラプちゃんのために練習しましたよ！
I practiced for Lapu-chan's sake!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
ち、ちゅろも…ありがとな…
A-And for Choco too... thanks...
まあ、当然…
Well, of course...
おっ、おいおいおい待て待て待て！
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait!
今回のライブ、我が輩、アイドルを目指していってて。
In this live, I'm aiming to be an idol.
どうですか？どうですか？
How is it? How is it?
黙んねよ！黙んねよ！
Shut up! Shut up!
まあパッションは完璧だったよね！
Well, the passion was perfect!
まあ、パッションはね！パッションは！
Well, the passion! The passion!
でもアイドルはな、パッションだけじゃ足りなくて、実は。
But for an idol, passion alone isn't enough, actually.
可愛くないと、ですよね。キュートじゃないと。
You have to be cute, right? You have to be 'cute'.
い、いや、頑張ります。ちょっと自信ない感じになっちゃったんですけど。
I-I'll do my best. I'm feeling a bit insecure now.
頑張ります。エールください、エール！
I'll do my best. Give me some support!
じゃあ次のキュートも頑張ってね！
Then, do your best in the next 'cute' part too!
えっ、なんかちゃんとやるやん！ありがとな！
Oh, you're actually being serious! Thanks!
頑張ります！ありがとう！またね！バイバーイ！
I'll do my best! Thank you! See you! Bye-bye!
あっさりだな…あっさりじゃない？
That was abrupt... wasn't it?
待って待って、うえー！逃げんなよ！
Wait, wait, whoa! Don't run away!
申し訳ない。ありがとう、バイバーイ！
Sorry about that. Thank you, bye-bye!
その時空から…
At that time, from the sky...
不思議な光が降りてきたのです。
A mysterious light descended.
誰だ？誰だ？誰だ？
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
ナナです！
It's Nana!
うぉー！あまり近くで見ないでください！
Whoa! Please don't look too closely!
ウサミンパワーでメルヘンチェンジ！
Usamin Power, Merhen Change!
夢と希望の耳耳みみみみっけ
Found the ears of dreams and hope
ナナ！頑張っちゃうぞ！
Nana! I'll do my best!
ミミミン ミミミン ウーサミン！
Mimimin Mimimin Usamin!
ウサウサウサ ウーサミン！
Usa Usa Usa Usamin!
電波でオッケー！受信でオッケー！
Waves are OK! Reception is OK!
ウサミン ウサミン グルコサミン！
Usamin Usamin Glucosamine!
心はちゃんと通じてるんです
Our hearts are truly connected
キュート キューティー キューティクル！
Cute, Cutie, Cuticle!
歌うのオッケー！ダンスもオッケー！
Singing is OK! Dancing is OK!
ウサミン ウサミン プロビタミン！
Usamin Usamin Provitamin!
これでもちゃんとアイドルなんです
Even so, I'm a proper idol
ハートミー！ビリビリ！
Heart me! Zapping!
ウサミン！ウサミン！
Usamin! Usamin!
電車で向かえば一時間
It takes an hour by train
ウサミン！レム睡眠！
Usamin! REM sleep!
「あっ、ここ、ウサミン星じゃない！？」
"Ah, this isn't Planet Usamin!?"
「通り過ぎちゃった！あわわわわ！」
"I passed it! Oh no, oh no!"
「一・二・ナナ！」
"One, two, Nana!"
ウサミンパワーで！
With Usamin Power!
メルヘンチェンジ！
Merhen Change!
いち！にー！ななー！
ウサミンパワーでメルヘンチェンジ！
One! Two! Seven!
Usamin Power, Märchen Change!
みーんな大好き 好き好き大好き ウードッカン！
ウサミンハートに ウサミンハートに
I love everyone! I love you, love you so much! U-dokkan!
Usamin Heart! Usamin Heart!
きゅんきゅんきらめく きゅんきゅんきらめく
ほっ どんどん気持ち キャン！ラブリー17歳
Sparkling with excitement! Sparkling with excitement!
Whoa! My feelings are growing! Can! Lovely 17-year-old!
だいじなだいじなトキメキだもん
Because it's a very precious flutter in my heart!
ワン・ツー・セー・の・ハイ！
One, two, and... Here we go!
ミミミン ミミミン ウーサミン！
Mi-mi-min, mi-mi-min, U-samin!
ウサウサウサ ウーサミン！
Usa-usa-usa, U-samin!
全力オッケー 笑顔でオッケー
ウサミン ウサミン ドバドバミン
Full power, OK! With a smile, OK!
Usamin, Usamin, Doba-doba-min!
いつかはトップにのぼりつめます
ラ、ラブリ、ラブリミん
I will reach the top someday!
La, Lovely, Lovely-min!
発声オッケー 覇気もオッケー
ウサミン ウサミン スコポラミン
Voice OK! Ambition OK!
Usamin, Usamin, Scopolamine!
いつかアニメの主役になります ムーミミン
Someday I'll be the lead in an anime! Mu-mi-min!
ピリピリ ウサミ ウサミ
体力持つのは１時間
Piri-piri, Usami, Usami!
My stamina only lasts for an hour!
ウサミ フラフラミン
Usami, Fura-fura-min!
でも！永遠の17歳だったらまだまだいけますよー！
But! As an eternal 17-year-old, I can still keep going!
いち！にー！ななー！
One! Two! Seven!
ウサミンパワーで ウサミンパワーで
With Usamin Power! With Usamin Power!
メルヘンチェンジ！ メルヘンチェンジ！
Märchen Change! Märchen Change!
みーんな大好き 好き好き大好き ウードッカン！
I love everyone! I love you, love you so much! U-dokkan!
ウサミンハートに ウサミンハートに
きゅんきゅんきらめく きゅんきゅんきらめく
Usamin Heart! Usamin Heart!
Sparkling with excitement! Sparkling with excitement!
ほっ どんどん気持ち キャッ！乙女の秘密だよ
Whoa! My feelings are growing! Kyah! It's a maiden's secret!
だいじなだいじなトキメキだもん
Because it's a very precious flutter in my heart!
ラプラスの本当の姿を知っても
好きでいてくれますか？
Even if you learn La+'s true form,
will you still love me?
なーんてね！
Just kidding!
ピピュン！ ピピュン！
Pipyun! Pipyun!
まだまだいきますよー！
I'm still going!
ハイ！ ハイ！
Hai! Hai!
ピピュン！ ピピュン！
もういっかい！ もういっかい！
Pipyun! Pipyun!
One more time! One more time!
ウサミンパワーで ウサミンパワーで
With Usamin Power! With Usamin Power!
メルヘンチェンジ！ メルヘンチェンジ！
Märchen Change! Märchen Change!
みーんな大好き 好き好き大好き ウードッカン！
I love everyone! I love you, love you so much! U-dokkan!
ウサミンハートに ウサミンハートに
きゅんきゅんきらめく きゅんきゅんきらめく
Usamin Heart! Usamin Heart!
Sparkling with excitement! Sparkling with excitement!
ほっ どんどん気持ち キャッ！ラブリー17歳
Whoa! My feelings are growing! Kyah! Lovely 17-year-old!
だいじなだいじなトキメキだもん
Because it's a very precious flutter in my heart!
ワン・ツー・セー・の・ブイ！
One, two, and... Victory!
ミミミン ミミミン ウーサミン！
Mi-mi-min, mi-mi-min, U-samin!
ウサウサウサ ウーサミン！
Usa-usa-usa, U-samin!
ちょっと... はぁ... 皆さん...
Hold on... *pant*... Everyone...
吾輩のメルヘンデビューどうでしたか？
How was my 'Märchen Debut'?
えっとですね...
Well, you see...
今回はこのメルヘンデビューのためにですね...
For this 'Märchen Debut' specifically...
17kgの重りを付けて踊りました。嘘です。
I wore 17kg weights while dancing. That was a lie.
いつもよりちょっと重めの枷を
つけて踊ってみました。流石に...
I tried dancing with slightly heavier shackles than usual.
As expected...
思ったよりすごい疲れちゃってちょっと...
I got way more tired than I thought...
上手に歌えなかったんですけど
ダンスもちょっとアレなんですけど...
I couldn't sing that well, and my dancing was
a bit of a mess, but...
どうでしたか？ 頑張りました。
How was it? I gave it my all.
え、そして、何やら、え、メルヘンデビューを
ここの周年ライブで、え...
And also, since I performed 'Märchen Debut'
here at my anniversary live...
披露したということで、なんかバンダイナムコさんから
動画が届いているみたいです。
It seems a video message has arrived from
Bandai Namco.
ク、クレームだったらどうしよう。
ちょっと怖いんですけど、ちょっと見ていきましょう。
Wh-What if it's a complaint? I'm a bit scared,
but let's take a look.
モニター、お願いします。
Monitor, please.
はーい、えー、ラプラス・ダークネス様、
活動2周年おめでとうございます！
Hello! Lady La+ Darknesss,
congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
梅木さんじゃない！ そう、あのイベントのね...
It's Umeki-san! Right, from that event...
はい、えー、バンダイナムコエンターテインメントの
アイドルマスターライブイベントのプロデューサーをしております梅木と申します。
Yes. My name is Umeki, and I'm a producer of THE IDOLM@STER
live events at Bandai Namco Entertainment.
梅木さんだー！
It's Umeki-san!
早速ですね、活動2周年ということで、
この先5年、10年と末長く活動していただき...
Now, as it's your 2nd anniversary, I hope you'll
continue your activities for a long time—5, 10 years...
輝きの向こう側を目指していただければと思っております。
よろしくお願いします。応援してます。
And aim for 'the other side of the sparkle.'
Best regards. I'm rooting for you.
恐縮です！ 応援してます！
I'm honored! I'm rooting for you too!
はい、そしてですね、アイドルマスターシリーズの方も
負けないように頑張っていきたいと思っております。
Yes. And we'll also work hard so that
THE IDOLM@STER series won't be outdone.
いや、比べないでくださいよ。
Hey, don't compare us.
で、アイドルマスターシリーズですけれども、
来る、えー、12月9日、10日にですね、東京ドームでラブライブ！シリーズ...
As for THE IDOLM@STER series, coming up on
December 9th and 10th at Tokyo Dome, the Love Live! series...
「アイマス」30周年で歌合戦を開催いたします！
We'll be holding a song battle for 'iMAS' 30th anniversary!
イェーイ！
Yay!
この「異次元フェス アイドルマスター ラブライブ！歌合戦」にですね、
At this 'Ijigen Fes Idolmaster Love Live! Song Battle'...
ラプラス様が、アンバサダーとして就任いただくことが決定しております！
it's been decided that La+ will be appointed as an ambassador!
いや、そうなんだ。
Yeah, that's right.
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
ぜひですね、担当アイドル、担当アイドル以外のアイドルもですね、
I hope you'll produce not only your own favorite idols but other idols as well,
ラプラス様にプロデュースしていただき、歌合戦を盛り上げていただければと思います。
and help us make the song battle a huge success.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Looking forward to it.
いや、もちろん！
Of course!
はい、それでは活動2周年、おめでとうございました！
Well then, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
これからも引き続きアイドルマスター、よろしくお願いいたします。
Please continue to support Idolmaster.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
うめきさーん！あ、アイマス大好き元気おじさん。
Umeki-san! Ah, the energetic uncle who loves iMAS.
アイマス大好き元気おじさん、わーありがとうございます！
The energetic uncle who loves iMAS, wow, thank you so much!
なんと、アイマスシリーズのライブの企画運営を統括していらっしゃる、
Amazingly, we received a message from Umeki-san,
うめきさんからメッセージをいただきました！ありがとうございます！
who oversees the planning and operation of the iMAS series lives! Thank you!
そうです、なんとわたくしこの度ですね、ラブライブとアイマスの合同ライブ、
That's right, for the Love Live and iMAS joint live,
「異次元フェス」のアンバサダーに就任しました！ありがとう！イェーイ！
I've been appointed as an ambassador for 'Ijigen Fes'! Thank you! Yay!
ということでね、いやもう大好きなアイマスに、
So, I'm just so happy to be involved,
ちょっとでも携わるお仕事ができるっていうのが凄く嬉しくて嬉しくて。
even just a little bit, with my beloved iMAS.
いや、みんな異次元フェス注目してください！
Everyone, please keep an eye on Ijigen Fes!
ありがとう！いやーめっちゃ可愛かったでしょ吾輩。
Thank you! Wasn't I super cute?
キュートも完璧だ！ありがとう！
My cuteness is perfect too! Thank you!
次！
Next!
よし、これで全てのピースは揃った！
Alright, now all the pieces are in place!
これで吾輩は、まさに完璧で究極...
Now I am truly perfect and ultimate...
それやりたいだけだろ。
You just want to do that pose.
心なしか、薄汚れたオーラが変化してきている気がするよ。
I feel like my somewhat dingy aura is starting to change.
なんか、どんどん言い方酷くなってない？
Isn't the way you talk getting meaner?
正直、どこら辺が変わったか分からないでござるな。
To be honest, I don't see what's changed.
ああ、そんなチクチク言葉を投げかけては...
Now now, don't throw such prickly words...
ラプラスちゃんが燃え尽きてる。
La-plus-chan is burning out.
ラプラスちゃん。
La-plus-chan.
うわっ、そらさん！
Whoa, Sora-san!
ラプラスちゃんにとって、アイドルって何？
What is an idol to you, La-plus-chan?
それは、そらさんみたいに完璧で可愛くて、かっこよくて、
It's someone like you, Sora-san, who is perfect, cute, cool,
元気がもらえる最強で無敵なアイドルです！
and provides energy... the strongest and most invincible idol!
あと「っ」とか言わない！
And don't say things like 'ugh'!
そら先輩の前で「っ」とか言うな！
Don't say 'ugh' in front of Sora-senpai!
ラプラスちゃん、アイドルってね、
La-plus-chan, you know, being an idol...
完璧じゃなくてもいいんだよ。
doesn't mean you have to be perfect.
何回転んでも、笑顔で起き上がって頑張って、
Even if you fall many times, if you get up with a smile and try hard,
たとえ一人でも、その人のおかげで生きていける人がいたら、きっとそれが最高のアイドルだと思うの。
and if there's even one person who can keep living because of you, then I think that's the best idol.
ボソッと言うけど、ラプラスどのはこういうアイドルもののコンテンツにめっぽう弱いでござるからな。
Just whispering this, but La-plus-dono is extremely weak to this kind of idol-related content.
だから、ラプラスちゃんがなりたいものになろう。
So, let's become what you want to be, La-plus-chan.
アイドルでも、アイドルじゃなくても。
Whether that's an idol or not.
そらさん、ありがとうございます！
Sora-san, thank you so much!
あと結婚してください。
And please marry me.
どさくさに紛れても無理だろ。
Even if you try to slip it in, it's not gonna work.
いいんだよ、一緒に頑張ろうね。
It's okay, let's work hard together.
あと結婚は無理かな。
And I guess marriage is a no.
そりゃそうでござる。
That's naturally so.
えへへ。そらさん、吾輩何があっても諦めません！
Ehehe. Sora-san, I won't give up no matter what!
世界征服も、アイドル活動も、
Neither world domination, nor idol activities,
あとそらさんも！
nor Sora-san!
最後のはもう諦めろ。
Give up on the last one already.
うん、応援してるよ。
Yeah, I'm rooting for you.
あと結婚は無理かな。
And I guess marriage is a no.
そりゃそうでござる。
That's naturally so.
今なら、なんでもできる気がするもん！
I feel like I can do anything right now!
吾輩頑張っちゃうからねー！
I'm going to do my best!
ねぇ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give a huge amount of love
この命の使い方を
The way to use this life
君に愛されたい
I want to be loved by you
はい エコパの落とし穴
Yes, the pitfall of Ecopa
夢中にさせちゃうぞ
I'll make you obsessed with me
埼玉県から来ました
I came from Saitama Prefecture
フレッシュレモンになりたいの
I want to be a fresh lemon
ファンの方が恋人です
The fans are my lovers
真面目なアイドル 真面目にアイドル
A serious idol, seriously being an idol
年中無休 24時間 ずっと笑顔でうたっちゃうピース
Open all year, 24 hours a day, always singing with a smile, peace!
はい あなたの心にホールインワン
Yes, a hole-in-one to your heart
あなたのハートにアクセスします
Accessing your heart
みんなのドキドキにシュートします
Shooting into everyone's pounding hearts
なんでもいいからレスください
Give me a reaction, anything will do
禿げ気味の皆さん ぬぉー
To all the balding folks, nuoooh!
よし 今日も可愛い 小指ビーム
Alright, cute today too, Little Finger Beam!
ねぇ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
ずっと分からなかったけど
I didn't understand for a long time
幸せになりたい
But I want to be happy
エンジェルシャンプーの
I found the scent
香りをみつけたの
of angel shampoo.
歌で人の気持ち
So that I can brighten
明るくできるように
people's spirits with my songs,
きっと人生にくじけてる
because I'm sure there are people
人がいると思うから
who are discouraged in life.
はい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ
Shout more.
はい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ イェーイ
Shout more, yeah!
今日のハイライトは
Today's highlight is
めちゃくちゃアイドル
excessively idol.
はい めちゃくちゃ話すのが苦手
Yes, I'm very bad at talking.
可愛いつもり？ 気持ち悪い
Trying to be cute? Disgusting.
世界のルールを歌って
Singing the rules of the world,
踊って 破壊する
dancing, and destroying.
燃えろ 尊ぶ 燃えろ
Burn, revere, burn.
髪の毛見た目は純白 中身は真っ黒
Hair and looks are pure white, inside is pitch black.
ちょっぴりおバカな 小さな巨神
A slightly silly little giant god.
カンデラ 照射
Candela radiation.
イミテーション 向き合って 混ぜるだけ
Imitation, just face it and mix it.
あっという間に ミルキー
In the blink of an eye, milky.
ちんぷいぷい 魔法にかかれ
Chin-pui-pui, be under a spell.
あ、かかっちゃった
Ah, you fell for it.
トイレなんて行ったことないよ
I've never been to a toilet.
ピンクのマシュマロが出ます
Pink marshmallows come out.
3時のおやつはマカロンがよき
3 o'clock snack should be macarons.
ふわふわガール 在住中
Fluffy girl, currently residing.
ねえ アイドルって楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun.
いっぱい愛が舞ってる
Lots of love is dancing around.
ステージから見る景色が
The view from the stage
ずっと宝物さ
will always be a treasure.
ねえ もし君が絶望
Hey, even if you
したとしても君が
fall into despair,
必要な分の幸せは
was I able to give you
あげられていたかな？
the happiness you need?
はい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ あーっ！
Shout more, ahhh!
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ フー！
Shout more, whoo!
はい 360度 どこから見ても
Yes, 360 degrees, from anywhere you look,
アイドル
an idol.
出席番号 27 好きになってもいいですか？
Attendance number 27, may I like you?
僕の妹がこんなに可愛いわけがない 感動
My little sister can't be this cute. Moving.
ぷにぷに ぴちぴちでしょ
Squishy and fresh, right?
こんにち ぬげぬげ
Konnichi-nugenuge.
推せる 愛せる らんらんるー
Stannable, lovable, ran-ran-ruu.
今日も明日も明後日も
Today, tomorrow, and the day after,
キラキラパワー全開
sparkling power at full throttle.
頑張って いきます！
I'll do my best!
みんなの目線を いただきまゆゆ
Taking everyone's eyes, Itadak-Mayuyu.
泣き虫で 甘えん坊な みんなの妹
Crybaby and spoiled, everyone's little sister.
ねえ アイドルって楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun.
いっぱい愛が舞ってる
Lots of love is dancing around.
ステージから見る景色が
The view from the stage
ずっと宝物さ
will always be a treasure.
ねえ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol.
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give amazing love.
この命の使い道を
I want to be loved by you
君に愛されたい
with how I use this life.
はい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ
Shout more.
はい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ
Shout more.
はい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ
Shout more.
はい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to like me.
もっと大胆に
More boldly.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me.
もっと叫べ
Shout more.
一等賞突き抜けて
Burst through as number one,
キラキラ輝く
shining brightly.
頑張っていきまーしょい！
Let's do our best!
あー、ちょっと最近寒いなあ。
Ah, it's been a bit cold lately.
11月かあ。
It's November, huh.
もうラプラス・ダークネス1周年記念グッズ ラプラスTシャツで生活するのも限界だあ。
Living in just the La+ Darkness 1st anniversary T-shirt has reached its limit.
話は聞かせてもらいましたよ！
I've heard the talk!
どれ！
Let's see!
いやお姉さん、丁度いいですわ！
Hey sister, that's just perfect!
え、何が？
Eh, what is?
最近寒いよね！わかる！
It's been cold lately, right! I get it!
そんなあなたに！
For someone like you!
えーい、じゃん！
Here, ta-da!
ラプラス・ダークネス2周年記念グッズ、パーカー！
La+ Darkness 2nd Anniversary Goods, Hoodie!
パーカー
Hoodie
え、タイミングがいい！
Eh, what good timing!
そしてなんと、ステッカーも付いてきます！
And what's more, it comes with stickers!
ステッカー（3種入り）
Stickers (set of 3)
なんかお得感。
Feels like a good deal.
でもお高い...？
But is it expensive...?
セットで1万円以下！
Under 10,000 yen for the set!
食い気味！
Cutting me off!
でもパーカーとステッカーセットで買っても特典とかないとなあ。
But even if I buy the hoodie and sticker set, there needs to be a bonus.
セットで買ってくれた人限定で直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード付いてくる！
Exclusively for those who buy the set, a handwritten signed cheki-style bromide card is included!
直筆！？
Handwritten!?
活動2周年記念フルセット 購入特典
2nd Anniversary Activities Full Set Purchase Bonus
全員！？
For everyone!?
え、ボイスも！？
Eh, a voice too!?
買った！ありがとうございます！
Bought! Thank you very much!
じゃあください、今寒くて。
Then please give it to me, I'm cold right now.
届くのは来年！
It arrives next year!
そんなバカなー！
No way!
活動2周年記念 記念グッズ 2種
・パーカー ・ステッカー（3種入り）
2nd Anniversary Activities Memorial Goods (2 types)
- Hoodie - Stickers (Set of 3)
活動2周年記念フルセット 購入特典
・直筆サイン入り チェキ風ブロマイドカード ・特典ボイス
2nd Anniversary Activities Full Set Purchase Bonus
- Handwritten signed cheki-style bromide card - Bonus voice